YA / YOUSSEF ABOUELGHAR

youssef aboualghar@hotmail.com | +1 (551) 363-7024 | Bayonne, NJ 07002 | www.linkedin.com/in/youssef-aboualghar-al3066111

SUMMARY

A Full-stack developer in 3D modeling and graphic design. Developed an AI to streamline the design process by over 90%. Experienced with a range of programming languages and tools. Managed full software development lifecycle. Leading a team of three people.

AWARDS

May 2021

Nilepreneurs

 Conix Incubation received 1st award for launching Conix Al platform. Jun 2016.

ECG University to work

Our team earned 1st place in the competition.

SKILLS

3D Modeling:

• Rhinoceros 3D and Grasshopper.

Graphic Design:

• Photoshop, Illustrator, and InDesign.

Scripting/Dev:

• C#, Unity, Java, and Python.

Web Dev:

- Node.js, React, Angular, SQL (MySQL, MSSQL), Javascript, and typescript.
- PHP and Pure/Vanilla JS(JavaScript).
- Git, REST APIs, GitHub, AWS.

LANGUAGES

English

Native/Bilingual Arabic

Native/Bilingual

French

Professional Level Japanese

Intermediate

EXPERIENCE

Jul 2021 - Present

Senior Computational Designer/Full Stack Developer | Conix.ai

- switched to Angular/React and Node.js to improve scalability, increasing deployment efficiency by 50%.
- Managed DevOps through GoDaddy and then Cloudflare, reducing costs by 33%.
- Wrote database using MYSQL migrating from MSSQL.
- Secured \$1.2 million in funding and reduced design time by over 90% through Al development.
- Deployed our stack on AWS, serving over 1000 users.
- Currently managing a team of computational designers and developers.
- The full result is at www.conix.ai (you can operate the AI).

Jul 2017 - Jun 2021Jul 2017 - Jun 2021

Computational Designer/Full Stack Developer | Yusuf Fahmy Architects (YFA)

- Worked in a startup environment
- Developed custom tools in C# and .NET, combining architecture and coding for innovative solutions.
- Designed algorithms in Java and Processing to automate 3D modeling.
- Built physics engines from scratch using C# and Grasshopper.
- Created and maintained company website using JS and ASP.NET.
- Wrote database using MSSQL
- Incorporated PHP and React for our web design.
- Secured first enterprise client seed round to found startup Conix.Al
- Deployed on Digital Ocean cutting costs by 20%.

Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

Intern | ECG University to Work

- Introduced to coding in C# and VB as part of the design process.
- Graduated with an A+ rating (above 95%). Showcased research and sustainable design expertise.

EDUCATION

Sep 2012 - Jun 2017.

Bachelor's Degree in Architecture | MODERN ACADEMY

- Graduated with a B+ average (above 80%). Demonstrated creative computational design skills.
- Conducted innovative research and implemented new systems. Developed concepts using beginner C++.